# Juan Chavez

## Software Engineer



juanchavez.me



github.com/je-chavez



linkedin.com/in/juanenriquechavez



(408) 460-7693



juanenriquechavez@outlook.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Passionate and enthusiastic software developer with 2 years of relative experience in mobile and web development. Thrives in fast-paced teams, excels under pressure and creatively solves problems. Looking to start his career in Software Engineering.

#### SKILLS



#### **EDUCATION**

Western Governors University B.S Software Development Expected Graduation April 2020

**CIW Certifications**Site Development Associate

#### **PROJECTS**

### **Gub, Mobile Application**

React Native, Node.js, Microsoft Azure

Developed a mobile application that helps gamers discover gaming content. Published on Android and iOS app stores with 35 combined total active installs.

**Tools used**: JavaScript, Azure CosmosDB, Azure Kubernetes Service, Azure Container Registry, Node.js, React Native, Docker

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Cloud Technical Expert @ Microsoft

Sep 2019 - Present | Palo Alto, CA

Responsible for cloud services deployment, customer relationship management and enterprise technical advising.

- Drove product adoption and usage through success trainings with companies such as Dolby, Opportun and more.
- Performed service sales and deployments of Microsoft 365 and Office 365 with post-deployment support.

#### Services Advisor @ Microsoft

April 2018 - Sep 2019 | Palo Alto, CA

Specialized in computer hardware and software repairs. Individually responsible for maintaining tools and operations.

- Developed a PowerApp web application that automates various cross-team operational duties.
- Developed Power Automation Flows to create scheduled reporting and scheduling for the team.
- Ability to translate complex problems into a series of steps, understandable by customers, to solve technical issues.

## Software Engineer Intern @ Ambii

Sept 2018 - Dec 2018 | San Jose, CA

Designed and developed new features for a fast-paced startup.

- Designed and integrated data caching using an in-memory database (Redis) improving load times.
- Developed AutoPlay between clients by using sockets resulting in synchronized playback.

## Program Manager Apprenticeship @ Microsoft

Jan 2018 - April 2018 | Redmond, WA

Nominated and selected for an apprenticeship, helping bridge the gap between physical stores and engineering teams.

- Presented high impact bugs to senior leadership and followed up with resolutions that improved Windows.
- Led Retail Awareness Trainings showcasing Microsoft Stores to various engineering teams within COSINE.